# William Spalding

🎙 Hayward, California 🗷 williamspalding00@gmail.com 🗖 5107318959 📠 in/william-spalding/ 🕳 www.williamspalding.com

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced software developer, and detail oriented professional with a passion for problem solving and automation. Self motivated, with vast academic and real-world knowledge of software analysis, design and development and love to learn new things and improve my skillsets.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Jr Software Developer

Ji Software Develo Kodor

July 2020 - Present, Irvine, California

- · Lead in development of [U]'s class privacy system using .NET and AzureSQL. Integrated OAuthorization with [U]'s frontend and web API's to protect private classes from unwanted users, without limiting access to public classes.
- $\cdot \ Decreased \ [U] \ page \ loading \ times \ by \ over \ 90\% \ by \ minimizing \ and \ optimizing \ database \ quires, utilizing \ caching \ methods, and \ removing \ inefficient \ and \ redundant \ code.$
- $\cdot$  Redesigned and implemented overhaul of [U]'s badge system, across web and mobile platforms. Streamlined and fool-proofed the creation, deletion, and editing of badges, while retaining full backwards compatibility.
- Integrated OpenGraph and Twitter sharing protocols, allowing [U] instructors and students to share their share their classes and profiles on the largest social media platforms with a single click; automatically passing necessary metadata and personalized messages.

#### **Software Engineer**

All in One Home Services

June 2019 - August 2020, Dublin, CA

- Designed and built new company website, that generated 33 new job orders in the first month, by creating an easy to use interface for customers to submit new job orders.
- Streamlined website design, by designing new back-end database and interface, allowing management to easily edit company website without programming knowledge.
- · Migrated database and website hosting, decreasing cost of website by \$500 per year, by moving domain and server hosting to AWS. Single handedly managed company's AWS account, EC2 instance, PostgreSQL database, and AWS SES service until the sale of the company.

#### **Software Engineering Intern**

Arista Networks Inc.

June 2018 - September 2018, San Mateo, CA

- Designed and implemented asynchronous automated data collection systems using REST API, synchronizing company data across over 15 external services and databases.
- Developed an integrated Zendesk web application allowing the Arista Human Resources department to quickly, and easily, access the Arista Asset Database; decreasing the time needed to answer asset requests by over 80%, and reducing the number of people required to 1.
- · Built SSL Certificate signing services for Arista database servers, using sha-256, to automatically issue and authenticate new authentication certificates for Arista web servers for clients.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelors of Science in Computer Science**

University of California, Riverside · Riverside, CA · 2019

### **PROJECTS**

#### Coloram

September 2019

• Designed and built iOS mobile game using Xcode, Swift, and SpriteKit that included 10 levels of increasingly difficult gameplay, each with a continuous scoreboard and customizable sprites and received a 5 star rating on the apple app store.

#### **BattleShips**

November 2019

· Created a React web app for the popular game Battleships and implemented a easy to use interface allowing players to play against either another human or a computer.

### **SKILLS**

Front end: HTML, Javascript, CSS, React, Razor, JQuery, Ajax

Back end: PHP, Django, Flask, Node.js, .Net Core, Api design

iOS development: XCode, Swift

Databases: mySQL, Redis, Postgres, Azure

Development: C, C++, C#, Python, Swift, JS, PHP, UAT testing, AB testing

Machine Learning: Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, Scikit - Learn